A Guide to the William L. Groth Papers 1960s-1980s
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
William L. Groth Papers 1960s-1980s
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 245
.18 linear feet
William L. Groth
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The materials were donated to the Department by Mr. Groth in 1987.
Biographical/Historical Information
Born 24 March 1907 in Ada, Ohio, William L. Groth attended the University of Richmond from 1928 until 1932. Mr. Groth joined the Virginia State Police in March of 1934 and was promoted to Sergeant in 1938. He made Lieutenant in 1941 and Captain in 1942. In 1949, Mr. Groth was made Deputy Administrator of the Governor's Highway Safety Committ in 1949. Under his administration, Virginia received national awards for public safety education and organization of public transport for safety.
In 1955, Mr. Groth became the Director of Public Safety for the City of Richmond. Under his administration, the City consolidated the Bureau of Weights and Measures with the Division of Air Pollution Control and Boiler Inspection, lengthened and strengthened the police and fire recruit training, the construction of a new lockup at 6th and Marshall Streets, and a new administrative office for the 1st Police Division. He also implemented the use of police dogs and decentralized ambulance service for the city.
Scope and Content Information
The collection is composed published materials about Richmond from the late 1960s and early 1970s.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- City of Richmond Civic Center (Box 1)
- Five Thousand Days in Richmond (Box 1)
- Hurricane Agnes...The Richmond Flood June 22, 1972 (Box 1)
- Richmond and the James (A Plan for Conservation Recreation Beautification) (Box 1)
- Richmond Reports (Supplement to the Richmond News Leader) 1971 (Box 1)
- Richmond Reports (Supplement to the Richmond News Leader) 1971-1972 (Box 1)
- The Commonwealth-The Magazine of Virginia March 1967 (Box 1)
- The Greater Richmond Story (Box 1)
- The Richmond News Leader July 27, 1983 (Box 1)
- Virginia Town and City (Vol. #7-9) September 1972 (Box 1)
- Virginia Water Pollution Control Association Story (Box 1)
- Written Paper- The City of Richmond, Virginia (Box 1)
- Your Richmond City Government (Box 1)